# **Gregory Witek**

hello@gwitek.com +31 (0) 6 25 04 07 51 Rotterdam, Netherlands

#### **PROFILE**

I am an ambitious engineering manager and software developer with a total of 9 years of professional experience. I write code, I participate and speak at conference, I build and teams, and mentor developers. I've worked in multiple industries including travel, fintech and adtech, both for product companies and software houses.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

## 2019 — now: Lead Full-Stack Developer at NGTI/Swisscom (Netherlands)

- Led 2 projects in parallel: hybrid mobile application built in Angular, and internal big data panel created with Vue.js
- Led hiring efforts in web development team
- Participated in multiple stages of project development: designing applications architecture, supporting developers on daily basis, implementing features, maintaining code quality

## 2017 — 2018: Head of Engineering at Ascenda (Singapore)

- Managed 3 teams of engineers with up to 16 direct reports
- Initiated and set up the first overseas team of Engineering (in Manila, Philippines) and growing development team from 8 to 20 people
- Overhauled team structure and processes as the company kept growing and maturing
- Mentored developers on all stages in their careers, from interns to team leaders
- Participated in team-wide and company-wide performance review
- Initiated and led efforts in moving company to a remote-first culture
- Continued to be a hands-on engineer, with working time split between programming and management activities

#### 2015 — 2017: Lead Software Engineer at Ascenda (Singapore)

- Helped the company to grow from 2 to 8 engineers (and to around 20 by the end of 2018)
- Designed and led building 2 main company products: a web-based white label travel booking platform and API-based loyalty currency exchange
- Led effort in implementing major functionalities, including a hotel search engine written in Elixir
- Collaborated with other departments in removing bottleneck through design of internal tools
- Led multiple team meetings, including sprint planning and retrospective
- Introduced and organised internal workshops

#### **2014** — **2015**: Freelancing

- Built multiple client projects using Ruby on Rails, Backbone.js and AngularJS
- Worked remotely yet responsively for customer across multiple timezones

#### 2012 — 2013: Software Developer at Fyber (Germany)

• Optimised ad serving engine to handle up to 300,000 requests/minute

- Led building advertiser self-service panel
- Worked closely with product managers to support data-driven decisions

## 2012: Back-End Developer at Flywire (Spain)

- Built an international money transfer platform that helps to reduce bank fees
- Worked on service oriented architecture, supported by libraries like AMQP and by a custom single sign-on solution

#### 2009 — 2011: Software Developer at Netguru (Poland)

- Worked on multiple client projects, including on-line games, e-commerce site as well as HR tools
- Led workshops for students and helped in growing company by organising student internships

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Back-end development with Ruby, Elixir, Scala, Python, Node.js
- Front-end development with TypeScript, Angular, Vue.js, React.js
- Proficiency with both SQL and NoSQL databases
- Experience with multiple AWS services
- Experience with heavy-traffic, scalable applications, service oriented architecture
- Basic familiarity with machine learning, Kubernetes, Hashicorp tools

### **EDUCATION**

Poznan University of Technology: BSc in Computer Science, 2007 – 2011

Poznan University of Technology: MSc in Computer Science (specialisation Software Engineering), 2011 – 2012

#### **OTHERS**

I occasionally contribute to open source projects. I used to maintain Sorcery, a popular authentication library.

I spoke at several technical conferences, including EuRuKo (European Ruby Conference), WebExpo Prague, RedDotRuby in Singapore, RubyConf Taiwan as well as Codemotion Berlin.

I used to co-organise local meetups for Ruby Developers in Poland and Singapore, as well as meetups for Elixir and Erlang developers in Singapore.

I volunteered as a programming coach in Singapore, Poland and Spain.

I speak Polish (native), English (very fluent) and Spanish (conversational). Currently I study Dutch.